Guide to the Crimson Circle Records 1919-1971
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Crimson Circle Records
1919-1971
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Cage 940
Crimson Circle (State College of Washington)
0.75 Linear feet of shelf space 2 Boxes
Records of the Crimson Circle, affiliated with Omicron Delta Kappa, at Washington State University. Includes minutes, membership records, a historical sketch, correspondence, and newspaper clippings.
The Crimson Circle was chartered at what was then the State College of Washington on March 5, 1912 as a society of students recognizing achievement in the fields of sports, student government, publications, and academics, among others. The group was disbanded in spring 1929 by the campus Discipline Committee, following breaches of conduct and the academic suspension of several members. However, the organization reformed with a new Constitution and a new founding class on February 9, 1931. The Crimson Circle became a chapter of Omicron Delta Kappa (ODK) on Dec. 12, 1959. Over time the group faded; its last active mention in the student paper was in August, 2000, and its ODK charter was officially recalled on July 1, 2004. On Sept. 15, 2017, an ODK chapter was opened at WSU Tri-Cities.
This collection contains records of the Crimson Circle at Washington State College (later Washington State University) between 1919 and 1971. The collection includes correspondence, minutes, membership information, organization historical records, and a book of newspaper clippings regarding the organization.
Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject. Membership lists and membership pins are located out of order at the back of the collection due to their different sizes.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Bob Jonas of Moscow, ID, a former advisor to the Crimson Circle, donated this collection to the Washington State University Libraries on July 11, 1991 (MS.1991.33). A few items donated by Carl Morrow in the 1930s and retained within the WSU Publications collection (WSU 89-2) were moved into this collection when it was processed in 2020.
A Crimson Circle sweater is held in MASC in the WSU Ephemera and Realia Collection (SC 10).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Crimson Circle (State College of Washington) -- Records and correspondence.; Omicron Delta Kappa. Crimson Circle -- Records and correspondence.; State College of Washington -- History -- Sources.; State College of Washington -- Students.; Washington State University -- History -- Sources.; Washington State University -- Students.; Omicron Delta Kappa. Crimson Circle.
Greek letter societies -- Washington (State) -- Pullman -- Records and correspondence.
Colleges and Universities; Student Life
- Constitution, 1931, and Clippings, 1931-1936 (bound volume). (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence., 1929-1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence., 1940-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence., 1950-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence., 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence., 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence., 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Forms, blank., undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- “The History of the Crimson Circle.”, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Notes for “The History of the Crimson Circle” (bound volume)., 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Minute book (bound volume). Includes 1920 constitution for the Cougar Guards., 1919-1928 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Minute book (bound volume)., 1932-1947 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Minutes., 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Petition for a charter of the Omicron Delta Kappa society., 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Membership list, 1912-1959. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Membership pins (3)., undated (Box 2, Folder 17)